<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Dr. Alistair Bailey</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Dr. Alistair Bailey</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Display Jupyter Notebooks with Academic</title>
      <link>/post/jupyter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/jupyter/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;from IPython.core.display import Image
Image(&#39;https://www.python.org/static/community_logos/python-logo-master-v3-TM-flattened.png&#39;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./academic_0_0.png&#34; alt=&#34;png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;print(&amp;quot;Welcome to Academic!&amp;quot;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Welcome to Academic!
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;install-python-and-jupyter&#34;&gt;Install Python and Jupyter&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.anaconda.com/distribution/#download-section&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Install Anaconda&lt;/a&gt; which includes Python 3 and Jupyter notebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, for advanced users, install Jupyter notebook with &lt;code&gt;pip3 install jupyter&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;create-a-new-blog-post-as-usual-https-sourcethemes-com-academic-docs-managing-content-create-a-blog-post&#34;&gt;Create a new blog post &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/managing-content/#create-a-blog-post&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;as usual&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Run the following commands in your Terminal, substituting &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;MY_WEBSITE_FOLDER&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;my-post&lt;/code&gt; with the file path to your Academic website folder and a name for your blog post (without spaces), respectively:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;cd &amp;lt;MY_WEBSITE_FOLDER&amp;gt;
hugo new  --kind post post/my-post
cd &amp;lt;MY_WEBSITE_FOLDER&amp;gt;/content/post/my-post/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;create-or-upload-a-jupyter-notebook&#34;&gt;Create or upload a Jupyter notebook&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Run the following command to start Jupyter within your new blog post folder. Then create a new Jupyter notebook (&lt;em&gt;New &amp;gt; Python Notebook&lt;/em&gt;) or upload a notebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;jupyter notebook
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;convert-notebook-to-markdown&#34;&gt;Convert notebook to Markdown&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;jupyter nbconvert Untitled.ipynb --to markdown --NbConvertApp.output_files_dir=.

# Copy the contents of Untitled.md and append it to index.md:
cat Untitled.md | tee -a index.md

# Remove the temporary file:
rm Untitled.md
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;edit-your-post-metadata&#34;&gt;Edit your post metadata&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open &lt;code&gt;index.md&lt;/code&gt; in your text editor and edit the title etc. in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/front-matter/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;front matter&lt;/a&gt; according to your preference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To set a &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/managing-content/#featured-image&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;featured image&lt;/a&gt;, place an image named &lt;code&gt;featured&lt;/code&gt; into your post&amp;rsquo;s folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For other tips, such as using math, see the guide on &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;writing content with Academic&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An unmet need for data science training</title>
      <link>/post/unmet-data-science-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/unmet-data-science-training/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This post was motivated in part by
&lt;a href=&#34;https://masalmon.eu/2018/07/16/soapbox/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Maëlle Salmon&amp;rsquo;s post about blogging&lt;/a&gt;
and secondly from discussion with &lt;a href=&#34;http://laurajanegraham.github.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Laura Graham&lt;/a&gt; about my long term mission is to convince the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.southampton.ac.uk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;University of
Southampton&lt;/a&gt; (here in the UK) of the need to provide some
minimum data science training and support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The aim is to try to define the problem(s) a bit better and also a bit of a cry for help. I appreciate that none of this may be novel, but I needed to get
it written down and out of my head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;some-preliminaries&#34;&gt;Some preliminaries&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, a few vital statistics about me at the time of writing: 23 years since
I started work in the TV industry, 10 years since finishing my Engineering
degree and starting in immunology, 5 years since I finished my PhD, 3 years since
I started working in proteomics, and 3 years since I started learning R through the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/specializations/jhu-data-science&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;John Hopkins&lt;/a&gt;. (I still haven&amp;rsquo;t completed the capstone.)
And finally 1 year since I did &lt;a href=&#34;https://datacarpentry.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Data Carpentry&lt;/a&gt; instructor training.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning R and about the related data science issues through the community has
completely changed the way I work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, I&amp;rsquo;ve currently got four related soapbox issues:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;establishing if there is an unmet need for data science training&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;establishing best practices in delivering data science training&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;making the case for the data science officer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;biological data science&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first and second issues are the subject of this post as they are so
closely related.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third issue follows the first two, but perhaps even trickier: this is my
proposal that just as
one should have experimental officers for the purpose of training and
development of skills in the laboratory, who are permanent members of staff and not on fixed contracts and thus retaining knowledge within the institution, these should exist for data skills. It&amp;rsquo;s a subject
worthy of a separate post. And to be honest even if I could gather the
evidence to convince myself, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure in the current political and
economic climate of metric chasing I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to convince those in charge of
it&amp;rsquo;s merits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fourth issue also needs a separate post, but contains issues such as how
to communicate between experimenters and informaticians, and how to deal with
the fact that (in my experience) experiments evolve with each replicate whereas analysts would like to have all data sets generated in a standard way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;rsquo;s where I&amp;rsquo;m coming from, but returning to the matter at hand I&amp;rsquo;ve
identified a number of issues which I&amp;rsquo;d love to investigate and get input on,
and I expect there are others I&amp;rsquo;ve not thought of. Ultimately, I want to
approach this as a scientist. My working assumption is that there is an unmet
need for more data science training and support, but I always consider it
possible that I am mistaken, and I&amp;rsquo;d like to take an evidence based approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;issues&#34;&gt;Issues&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;identification&#34;&gt;Identification&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pretty much everyone has data and has to analyse data, whether they are an
archaeologist, biologist, social scientist, art historian or an engineer. I
personally consider writing a formula in an excel spreadsheet coding. Therefore
I assume almost everyone in academia codes to one degree or another. But when
I turn to my neighbours (biologists) and ask them if they code they say No. They don&amp;rsquo;t identify as coding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, when I attend events such as those for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://rsg.soton.ac.uk/research-software-community&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;research software
community&lt;/a&gt; organised by
my excellent colleagues in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://software.ac.uk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Software Sustainability Institute&lt;/a&gt; it appears to be predominantly engineers, physicists
and computer scientists in attendance. Which also means it is predominantly
men. The third area these events highlight is the difference between those who
predominately code to analyse data, and those who are more concerned with other aspects of coding such as machine control or code efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coding for me has been a necessary side effect of becoming a better scientist,
not an end itself, and I suspect, but don&amp;rsquo;t know that this would be true of
lots of other people, regardless of seniority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which leads me to two questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do we reach those who work with data, but who don&amp;rsquo;t identify as coders?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And how do we establish if there is an unmet need amongst these individuals?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To this end I created a draft &lt;a href=&#34;https://goo.gl/forms/UdWHrKv0FSjWg1Lw2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Data Analysis Survey Google Form&lt;/a&gt;. The aim was to create a survey that could be
completed in a couple of minutes and ideally carried out face-to-face. Emails
just get deleted and face-to-face may yield a more representative sample of the
University population.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if this is a good idea, the challenge I currently face is actually
carrying out the survey. I really need a group of like minded individuals to get it done. I&amp;rsquo;d be interested to know if anyone has done this before and how
they did it. Or if there is a better way forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;inclusivity&#34;&gt;Inclusivity&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inclusivity is bound up with identification, and although I&amp;rsquo;ve not addressed
it in my draft survey, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be surprised if it is part of why some people
don&amp;rsquo;t identify as coding. They don&amp;rsquo;t feel welcome. Following examples such the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.carpentries.org/topic_folders/policies/code-of-conduct.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;carpentries code of conduct&lt;/a&gt; this would need to be part of any data science
training set-up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;evidence-base&#34;&gt;Evidence base&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we can identify those who would benefit from
training/support, the next question is how do we establish what works best?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do biologists need something different from social scientists?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do post-graduates need something different from post-docs?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can we demonstrate to principal investigators that learning data science skills is not a waste of time?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perhaps most importantly of all, can we demonstrate that it brings value to the University? (They have the money.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t have any answers at the moment, but as far as I&amp;rsquo;m aware no-one is gathering information about what works and what doesn&amp;rsquo;t work here in Southampton. If anyone has ideas on about how to assess the efficacy of data
science training or knows of studies, please let me know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;data-science-skills-as-academic-infrastructure&#34;&gt;Data science skills as academic infrastructure&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the last 10 years I&amp;rsquo;ve sat in numerous meetings where statistical/
informatics training and support have been proposed across biology and
medicine, and yet we still don&amp;rsquo;t have a bioinformatics core or any
standardised University wide training. I don&amp;rsquo;t know why, but working
assumption is that is in part because these proposals are ad-hoc and based
upon anecdote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In comparison, in Southampton we have &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.southampton.ac.uk/isolutions/staff/iridis.page&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;a large super computer&lt;/a&gt; that is key to
many researchers. My understanding is that it only exists because of two years work to establish a business case throughout the University for such an infrastructure project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me, this suggests that we should consider data science skills as part of our infrastructure and approach as an issue worthy of sufficient resources to
investigate systematically. And if this case is made, invested in to a similar
degree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;timing-delivery-and-cognitive-load&#34;&gt;Timing, delivery and cognitive load&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another anecdotal observation frequently made by postgraduate students when they start is that they get hours of inductions and workshops before they&amp;rsquo;ve
generated any data or even understand their project. This makes little sense
both in terms of the cognitive load of such a data dump or in terms of telling
someone something weeks, or possibly months in advance of it&amp;rsquo;s utility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with other issues, I don&amp;rsquo;t have a clear idea of how to address this, but
we need to consider this problem when thinking about training. I subscribe to
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.datacamp.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;DataCamp&lt;/a&gt; as it provides the flexibility for me to
learn when it&amp;rsquo;s convenient or when a specific problem arises. What it lacks
however is the invaluable face-to-face discussion of a bespoke situation that occurs in workshops or with a colleague.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My feeling is that there needs to be a range of resources available: on-line
materials, user groups and peer led workshops for example. And my favourite idea: The Data Science Officer. It&amp;rsquo;s another reason why we need an evidence base to work from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-get-started&#34;&gt;How to get started?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s my non-exhaustive list of challenges to getting data science training
off the ground here in Southampton. And whilst it doesn&amp;rsquo;t exclude one thing to
do another, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure whether we should be starting by trying to get a useR
group going to gauge the demand, or focusing on the survey, or doing something
else? Time is limited always, and I don&amp;rsquo;t know what is most effective. One of
my other concerns is that doing things for free always lets the University off
the hook when they should be investing in their people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Maëlle said in her blog, one reason to write is voice amplification and I&amp;rsquo;d consider this post a good start if I get the attention of some helpful people either inside the University or in the community at large.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic: the website builder for Hugo</title>
      <link>/post/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create a free website with Academic using Markdown, Jupyter, or RStudio. Choose a beautiful color theme and build anything with the Page Builder - over 40 &lt;em&gt;widgets&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;themes&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;language packs&lt;/em&gt; included!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://academic-demo.netlify.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Check out the latest &lt;strong&gt;demo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of what you&amp;rsquo;ll get in less than 10 minutes, or &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/#expo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;view the &lt;strong&gt;showcase&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of personal, project, and business sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#install&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Setup Academic&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/get-started/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get Started&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;View the documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://discuss.gohugo.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ask a question&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/issues&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Request a feature or report a bug&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updating? View the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/update/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Update Guide&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/updates/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Release Notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support development of Academic:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://paypal.me/cushen&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Donate a coffee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.patreon.com/cushen&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Become a backer on Patreon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.redbubble.com/people/neutreno/works/34387919-academic&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Decorate your laptop or journal with an Academic sticker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://academic.threadless.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wear the T-shirt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/master/academic.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key features:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Page builder&lt;/strong&gt; - Create &lt;em&gt;anything&lt;/em&gt; with &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/page-builder/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;widgets&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;elements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edit any type of content&lt;/strong&gt; - Blog posts, publications, talks, slides, projects, and more!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create content&lt;/strong&gt; in &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Markdown&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/jupyter/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jupyter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/install/#install-with-rstudio&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RStudio&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plugin System&lt;/strong&gt; - Fully customizable &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/themes/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;color&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;font themes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Display Code and Math&lt;/strong&gt; - Code highlighting and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikibooks.org/wiki/LaTeX/Mathematics&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;LaTeX math&lt;/a&gt; supported&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Integrations&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://analytics.google.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Google Analytics&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://disqus.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Disqus commenting&lt;/a&gt;, Maps, Contact Forms, and more!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beautiful Site&lt;/strong&gt; - Simple and refreshing one page design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Industry-Leading SEO&lt;/strong&gt; - Help get your website found on search engines and social media&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Media Galleries&lt;/strong&gt; - Display your images and videos with captions in a customizable gallery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mobile Friendly&lt;/strong&gt; - Look amazing on every screen with a mobile friendly version of your site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multi-language&lt;/strong&gt; - 15+ language packs including English, 中文, and Português&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multi-user&lt;/strong&gt; - Each author gets their own profile page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Privacy Pack&lt;/strong&gt; - Assists with GDPR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stand Out&lt;/strong&gt; - Bring your site to life with animation, parallax backgrounds, and scroll effects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One-Click Deployment&lt;/strong&gt; - No servers. No databases. Only files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;color-themes&#34;&gt;Color Themes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Academic comes with &lt;strong&gt;day (light) and night (dark) mode&lt;/strong&gt; built-in. Click the sun/moon icon in the top right of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://academic-demo.netlify.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Demo&lt;/a&gt; to see it in action!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choose a stunning color and font theme for your site. Themes are fully customizable and include:&lt;/p&gt;









  
  


&lt;div class=&#34;gallery&#34;&gt;

  
  
  
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/getting-started/gallery/theme-1950s.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;1950s&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;/post/getting-started/gallery/theme-1950s_huaf5482f8cea0c5a703a328640e3b7509_21614_0x190_resize_lanczos_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/getting-started/gallery/theme-apogee.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Apogee&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;/post/getting-started/gallery/theme-apogee_hu4b45d99db97150df01464c393bfd17d4_24119_0x190_resize_lanczos_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/getting-started/gallery/theme-coffee-playfair.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Coffee theme with Playfair font&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;/post/getting-started/gallery/theme-coffee-playfair_hu446a8f670cc5622adcc77b97ba95f6c5_22462_0x190_resize_lanczos_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/getting-started/gallery/theme-dark.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Dark&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;/post/getting-started/gallery/theme-dark_hu1e8601ecc47f58eada7743fdcd709d3d_21456_0x190_resize_lanczos_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/getting-started/gallery/theme-default.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Default&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;/post/getting-started/gallery/theme-default_huba6228b7bdf30e2f03f12ea91b2cba0d_21751_0x190_resize_lanczos_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/getting-started/gallery/theme-forest.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Forest&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;/post/getting-started/gallery/theme-forest_hu4f093a1c683134431456584193ea41ee_21797_0x190_resize_lanczos_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/getting-started/gallery/theme-ocean.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Ocean&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;/post/getting-started/gallery/theme-ocean_hu14831ccafc2219f30a7a096fa7617e01_21760_0x190_resize_lanczos_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/getting-started/gallery/theme-strawberry.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Strawberry&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;/post/getting-started/gallery/theme-strawberry_hu36b0b347fcca08bd39e2df22dcedbdfb_39532_0x190_resize_lanczos_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  

  
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ecosystem&#34;&gt;Ecosystem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sourcethemes/academic-admin&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Academic Admin&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; An admin tool to import publications from BibTeX or import assets for an offline site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sourcethemes/academic-scripts&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Academic Scripts&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Scripts to help migrate content to new versions of Academic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;install&#34;&gt;Install&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can choose from one of the following four methods to install:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/install/#install-with-web-browser&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;one-click install using your web browser (recommended)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/install/#install-with-git&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;install on your computer using &lt;strong&gt;Git&lt;/strong&gt; with the Command Prompt/Terminal app&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/install/#install-with-zip&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;install on your computer by downloading the &lt;strong&gt;ZIP files&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/install/#install-with-rstudio&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;install on your computer with &lt;strong&gt;RStudio&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/get-started/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;personalize and deploy your new site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;updating&#34;&gt;Updating&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/update/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;View the Update Guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to &lt;em&gt;star&lt;/em&gt; the project on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; to help keep track of &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/updates&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;updates&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;license&#34;&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Copyright 2016-present &lt;a href=&#34;https://georgecushen.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;George Cushen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Released under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/blob/master/LICENSE.md&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;MIT&lt;/a&gt; license.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;div id=&#34;r-markdown&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;R Markdown&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see &lt;a href=&#34;http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can embed an R code chunk like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;summary(cars)
##      speed           dist       
##  Min.   : 4.0   Min.   :  2.00  
##  1st Qu.:12.0   1st Qu.: 26.00  
##  Median :15.0   Median : 36.00  
##  Mean   :15.4   Mean   : 42.98  
##  3rd Qu.:19.0   3rd Qu.: 56.00  
##  Max.   :25.0   Max.   :120.00
fit &amp;lt;- lm(dist ~ speed, data = cars)
fit
## 
## Call:
## lm(formula = dist ~ speed, data = cars)
## 
## Coefficients:
## (Intercept)        speed  
##     -17.579        3.932&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;including-plots&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Including Plots&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also embed plots. See Figure &lt;a href=&#34;#fig:pie&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt; for example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;par(mar = c(0, 1, 0, 1))
pie(
  c(280, 60, 20),
  c(&amp;#39;Sky&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;Sunny side of pyramid&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;Shady side of pyramid&amp;#39;),
  col = c(&amp;#39;#0292D8&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;#F7EA39&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;#C4B632&amp;#39;),
  init.angle = -50, border = NA
)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;fig:pie&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown_files/figure-html/pie-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;A fancy pie chart.&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 1: A fancy pie chart.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
